Hey everybody, welcome to this A1
English listening practice video. I hope
you're doing well and that you're ready
to practice your listening in English.
Today I'm going to talk about a trip
that I have planned for the future. My
family and I are gonna go to Greece in a
few months. We're really excited about
this and I'm currently planning this
trip. So, I wanted to talk about that in
today's video. Before I start talking
about that though, remember that you can
sign up for my training if you need help
with your pronunciation or your
listening. And if you want to get better
at those skills, you can join my
membership to receive my training for
that. The link is down below. open the
description by pressing the little more
button and then you'll see the links.
Okay, so let's talk about my trip to
Greece that I'm going to take. First of
all, why Greece? Why am I going there?
Well, Greece is one of the countries
that I have always wanted to visit. My
wife too, my wife and I have dreamed of
traveling to Greece for years. We tried
to plan a trip to Greece a couple times
actually, but the timing wasn't right
and we weren't able to go. But now we
finally have this trip planned and we're
really happy about that. Um, I love
traveling to Europe in general. I've
been to some different countries in
Europe and I always enjoy going there.
So, I like Europe in general and I'm
sure I'll like Greece as well. Uh I
particularly like warm European
countries like Greece perhaps, like
Spain, like Italy. uh the countries that
are further south
uh in Europe, those are the countries
that I'm most interested in visiting.
And Greece seems like a perfect place
for us to visit. It is warm. It has an
amazing history. Uh the history of
Greece is fascinating and of course when
people travel to Greece they have the
opportunity to learn about the different
areas of the country, the history of
these areas. So I really like that. Uh
and Greece is a beautiful country. Of
course, people love traveling to Greece
for the beautiful beaches and islands,
but not just that. There are beautiful
mountains, beautiful architecture,
ruins like of ancient buildings. There's
so much beauty there. Even just the
countryside.
Um, Greece is gorgeous. It's very
beautiful, right? Uh, and it's very
different from my country. It's very
different from the United States. And I
prefer to visit countries that are very
different from my own.
I just like that. I prefer to see things
that are um things that I don't see in
the US. I like to feel like I'm far away
from home. I like that type of
experience. So, for all of those
reasons, I want to go to Greece. But
there's also another reason which is
that I'm learning Greek uh at this time
and I would like to have some
conversations with locals when I'm in
Greece. I love being able to use the
languages that I learn. So that's
another motivation for uh going to
Greece as our destination, right? So I
hope that I can speak to some different
people in Greek when I'm there. Uh I
don't want to rely too much on my
English. I don't want to depend on uh
people speaking English to me. I want to
be able to have conversations in Greek.
Uh maybe I'll need uh to speak English
sometimes because I won't be able to say
everything that I want to say. But I
want to make the effort to talk to
people in Greek there. And people like
when you learn their language. People uh
appreciate this. And I like learning
other people's languages. So it's
perfect. Uh when you go to another
country and speak their language, they
appreciate that. and you get to practice
your skills in that language. So, I'm
excited about that. Uh, I have done that
in other countries before. Even my wife
did that once when we went to Italy. My
wife learned a little bit of Italian
before we went and I can remember that
she had uh some conversations with
different Italian local people that we
met there. It was really fun. So, uh
it's a great experience to use the local
language and uh people appreciate this
and you can practice your skills. You
can see um if you can uh communicate
with the locals, it's fun, right? So,
where exactly am I going in Greece?
Well, I'm actually not going to the
places that you probably expect. Uh, I'm
not going to any of the islands. I'm not
going to spend time at the beach. Uh,
that's not my type of vacation. I don't
really like beach vacations.
I'm going to go to a part of Greece that
is less touristic. There are fewer
tourists there. Uh this part of Greece
is called the Pelpine.
And specifically, we're going to take a
road trip through the Pelpine. We're
gonna uh rent a car and drive the car
through some of that region. We will
stay in a couple of cities like bigger
cities. Um one of them is Athens which
is not the Pelpine. Uh but we have to
arrive at Athens and fly out of Athens
of course. So, we're going to go there.
We'll also go to another city in the
Pelpines. And we will also stay in two
uh small towns in the Pelpines. I like
staying in small towns. I like that type
of experience when you take a road trip
and see some small towns and stay there
and talk to locals. It's fun. So, that's
what we're going to do. We'll see some
historical sites, of course. Uh, I'm
sure we will wander through different
cities and towns, meaning we'll just
walk through the streets and uh enjoy
the scenery. We will relax a little bit.
I think we won't do too much on this
trip. Uh we won't do anything really
adventurous probably. Uh we will enjoy
the scenery, enjoy the cities, the
towns, and of course the food. For us,
that's very important when we travel. We
love trying new food, local dishes.
This is really really interesting for
us. So that's one of the things that I'm
really excited about. And I'm also
excited because I don't travel very
often. I don't go out of the country
really often except for Mexico. Uh
Mexico is very close. Uh, and I go there
uh somewhat frequently, but besides
Mexico, I don't travel a lot. So, when I
do travel, it's really exciting. We're
really looking forward to this trip.
We're excited about this trip. I'm a
little nervous about speaking Greek in
Greece because I'm a beginner, but I'm
going to prepare before we go. I'm going
to prepare beforehand and hopefully I'll
be able to have some basic conversations
about different topics with people that
I meet there. and hopefully I can
understand what they say to me. It's
going to be a challenge, but I am
motivated to prepare for this trip and
I'm sure that I'll have the chance to
talk to people in Greek because as I
already mentioned, we're not going to
the super touristic places. We're going
to places that have fewer tourists, so
we'll probably have the chance to talk
to local people who don't speak English
really well. We'll see. But I'm looking
forward to that challenge. All right, I
hope that you enjoyed this video. I know
it was good practice for your listening.
Remember that you can get my training by
becoming a member of my membership and
you can start to practice your
listening, your pronunciation and
improve those skills with me with my
specialized training. So if you want
that, those links are in the description
below. You have to press the more button
if you can't see everything and it will
open the description and you can see the
links there. Okay. All right. Thank you
for watching this A1 English listening
practice video and I'll talk to you in
the next